Ben Baker

Software Engineer

 $978-204-4749 \cdot bbakercello@gmail.com \cdot Lowell, MA \cdot \underline{https://github.com/bbakercello} \cdot \underline{https://www.linkedin.com/in/ben-baker-cello/linkedin.com/in/ben-ba$

I'm a full-stack engineer who loves developing core infrastructures of technological products. I specialize in Javascript technologies (MERN stack - MongoDB, Express JS, React JS, Node JS) to build complete web applications. I develop elegant solutions using open

source tools and proactively look for ways to make systems run efficiently. In my free time as a cellist and composer, I write electronic

pieces of music using modular synthesizers and digital instruments.

SKILLS

Languages - JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Python, SQL, Mongo, JSON, Typescript, EJS, DTL | Database - PostgreSQL, MongoDB Libraries and Frameworks - React (class based and hooks), Express.js, Django, Jquery, Bootstrap, Semantic UI, Bulma Other - RESTful Routing, JSON api

SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT PROJECTS

Ratscrew | Fully interactive card game

August 2022

- Created a front-end browser-based page with Javascript, HTML and CSS to program a fun twist on the classic card game of War with additional rules for face cards
- Implemented JavaScript for game-mechanic functions and DOM manipulation to render card elements, asses win/loss conditions and provide user with game state information
- Formalized thorough comments throughout JavaScript to ensure ease of future code refactoring and potential collaborations on project

LandPost | Nature-focused social media platform

August 2022

- Led back-end programming in collaborative project to create entity relationships and program dynamic content display based off
 of user credentials and current session status
- Made RESTful API fetch calls to an Express, MongoDB, Node.js backend handling all create, read, update, delete (CRUD) operations, and tested all backend routes during development using Postman
- Used Mongoose to define schemas for MongoDB collections

Anonimusic | Anonymous audio forum

September 2022

- Created a session-based music sharing platform using Express and MongoDB on the backend and Cloudinary and React on the front-end
- Researched and implemented open-source components such as useState, Collapsible and React Audio Player to provide the user with an accessible and simple interface
- Wrote functions to dynamically generate randomized user names upon session start as well as conditional features such as username colors, permissions and time-stamped comments
- Styled and created the visual aspects using CSS and React Bootstrap

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Johnson String Instrument Quality Control and Fulfillment Director | Waltham, MA

June 2019 - July 2022

- Assumed full managerial responsibility of the entire workshop as a result of manpower overturn. Effectively developed a new
 online inventory system using Trello which led to more efficient outgoing order processes as well as overall positive upturn in
 customer satisfaction and feedback.
- Corresponded with shipping, sales and school service departments to develop more economical product storage policies.

 Directed workshop staff in implementation of new systems resulting in a more effective workflow as well as room for internal company growth.
- Inspected and prepared all outgoing instruments to insure company standards are exceeded. Delegated fulfillment tasks to staff leading to gaining a larger customer base with a same-day-shipping option.

AP Intego Customer Service Representative | Rochester, New York | Boston, MA

June 2015 - July 2017

• Took lead in management of payroll errors in Intuit billing system leading to a more functional customer service department. Error management led directly to improved retention and an overall increase in new clients.

- Collaborated with team members to solve data flow issues between insurance carrier sites and hosted systems. Solutions for data management resulted in stronger business relationships with insurance carriers.
- Communicated with customers via email to provide assistance in uploading payroll data and identifying insurance policy statuses for small businesses resulting in higher company reviews and stronger relations.

EDUCATION

GENERAL ASSEMBLY | REMOTE

Software Engineering Immersive

July 2022 - October 2022

Full-stack software engineering immersive student in an intensive, twelve-week, 450+ hour program focused on product development fundamentals, object-oriented programming, MVC frameworks, data modeling, and team collaboration strategies. Developed a portfolio of individual and group projects.

Boston Conservatory at Berklee | Boston, MA

Master of Contemporary Classical Music (MM)

August 2017 - May 2019

The Eastman School of Music | Rochester, NY

Bachelor of Cello Performance (MM)

August 2012 - May 2016